Endia Williams

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Portfolio

endia.dev

github.com/endiawilliams



Contact

contact@endia.dev

linkedin.com/in/endia-dev in

631-948-4568

Kansas City, MO 64133 \mathbf{Q}

Summary

I'm a full-stack engineer with a passion for responsive design & dynamic code. Having both a creative & a scientific turn of mind, I enjoy every part of the development process from start to finish. My diverse background gives me experience cooperating & communicating with a wide variety of people & allows me to see many perspectives. I take pride in what I do & always deliver the most efficient & elegant code possible.

Skills

HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, Flexbox, JavaScript, Python, React & React Native, Node, Express, Next.js, Expo, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Bcrypt, Passport, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud, CI/CD, Git & GitHub

Projects

Minesweeper

• Created a Minesweeper clone in HTML, CSS & JavaScript which utilizes recursion & DOM manipulation to reveal all adjacent empty squares when the user clicks on an empty square.

When in Roam

Developed a full-stack app with RESTful routing, full CRUD functionality & authentication using Bcrypt & Passport. Backend uses Node & Express.

BetterCupid + CI/CD

- Created a full-stack React app with full CRUD functionality & authentication using Bcrypt & Passport. Features Node & Express on the backend. Users can like each other, & every mutual like shows up on the Matches page.
- Implemented automated testing with Jest & Enzyme, continuous integration with GitHub Actions & continuous deployment to Google Cloud Kubernetes Engine.

Education

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly (2020)

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Liberal Arts

Ivy Tech Community College, Indianapolis, IN (2013-2014)

Experience

Client Coordinator

FrontStreet Facility Solutions, Ronkonkoma, NY (2018–2019)

Assisted 12 retail clients as needed to secure handymen for repair service, while meeting SLA requirements for response time & maintaining or exceeding a 20% profit margin.

Shift Lead

Speedway Convenience Store, Wading River, NY (2017-2018)

Data Entry Clerk

The American Legion, Indianapolis, IN (2014-2016)